{
  "theme": [
    {
      "Questions": {
        "theme": [
          {
            "Question": "Who is the alter ego of Spider-Man?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Peter Parker",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Miles Morales",
              "Eddie Brock",
              "Ben Reilly"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Peter Parker is the most well-known Spider-Man, created by writer Stan Lee and artist Steve Ditko in 1962."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What is the name of Batman's secret identity?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Bruce Wayne",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Clark Kent",
              "Diana Prince",
              "Hal Jordan"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Bruce Wayne first appeared in 'Detective Comics #27' in 1939, created by artist Bob Kane and writer Bill Finger."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which comic series features the character Hellboy?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Dark Horse Comics",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Marvel Comics",
              "DC Comics",
              "Image Comics"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Created by Mike Mignola, Hellboy first appeared in 'San Diego Comic-Con Comics #2' in 1993, published by Dark Horse Comics."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who is the archenemy of the X-Men?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Magneto",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Juggernaut",
              "Apocalypse",
              "Mystique"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Magneto, also known as Max Eisenhardt, first appeared in 'X-Men #1' in 1963 and is one of the most iconic X-Men villains."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which character is known as the fastest man alive in DC Comics?",
            "TrueAnswer": "The Flash",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Green Lantern",
              "Cyborg",
              "Aquaman"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The Flash, also known as Barry Allen, made his first appearance in 'Showcase #4' in 1956, created by writer Robert Kanigher and artist Carmine Infantino."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which team does the character Beast Boy belong to?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Teen Titans",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "X-Men",
              "Justice League",
              "The Avengers"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Beast Boy, also known as Garfield Logan, is a member of the Teen Titans, a superhero team published by DC Comics."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What is the real name of the superhero known as Captain Marvel?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Billy Batson",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Carol Danvers",
              "Mar-Vell",
              "Monica Rambeau"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Billy Batson is a young boy who transforms into the superhero Captain Marvel by saying the magic word 'Shazam!'"
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which comic book publisher is responsible for creating The Avengers?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Marvel Comics",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "DC Comics",
              "Dark Horse Comics",
              "Image Comics"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The Avengers were created by writer Stan Lee and artist Jack Kirby and first appeared in 'The Avengers #1' in 1963, published by Marvel Comics."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who is the main antagonist in the Batman comic series?",
            "TrueAnswer": "The Joker",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Bane",
              "Two-Face",
              "Ra's al Ghul"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The Joker, a criminal mastermind with a clown-like appearance, is Batman's most iconic and enduring archenemy."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which alien race is the main adversary of the Green Lantern Corps?",
            "TrueAnswer": "The Sinestro Corps",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "The Skrulls",
              "The Kree",
              "The Brood"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The Sinestro Corps, created by former Green Lantern Thaal Sinestro, is a mirror organization to the Green Lantern Corps."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What is the real name of the superhero known as Wonder Woman?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Diana Prince",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Kara Zor-El",
              "Donna Troy",
              "Cassie Sandsmark"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Diana Prince is an Amazonian princess and a founding member of the Justice League, created by writer William Moulton Marston and artist Harry G. Peter."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which superhero is known as the Man of Steel?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Superman",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Iron Man",
              "Thor",
              "Captain America"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Superman, also known as Kal-El, is one of the most iconic and enduring superheroes, first appearing in 'Action Comics #1' in 1938."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which character is a founding member of the Fantastic Four?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Reed Richards",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Johnny Storm",
              "Sue Storm",
              "Ben Grimm"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Reed Richards, also known as Mr. Fantastic, is a brilliant scientist and the leader of the Fantastic Four, created by writer Stan Lee and artist Jack Kirby."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who is the primary antagonist in the Spider-Man comics?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Green Goblin",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Doctor Octopus",
              "Venom",
              "The Lizard"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The Green Goblin, also known as Norman Osborn, is one of Spider-Man's most formidable and enduring foes, first appearing in 'The Amazing Spider-Man #14' in 1964."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which team does the character Storm belong to?",
            "TrueAnswer": "X-Men",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Teen Titans",
              "Avengers",
              "Justice League"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Storm, also known as Ororo Munroe, is a powerful mutant and a prominent member of the X-Men, created by writer Len Wein and artist Dave Cockrum."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What is the name of the newspaper where Clark Kent works as a reporter?",
            "TrueAnswer": "The Daily Planet",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "The Gotham Gazette",
              "The Daily Bugle",
              "The Metropolis Times"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The Daily Planet is a major metropolitan newspaper in the fictional DC Universe, where Clark Kent, also known as Superman, works as a reporter alongside Lois Lane."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which character is a prominent member of the Justice League and has a ring-based power?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Green Lantern",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "The Flash",
              "Wonder Woman",
              "Aquaman"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Green Lantern, also known as Hal Jordan, is a member of the intergalactic Green Lantern Corps and possesses a power ring that can create constructs based on the wielder's willpower."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who is the archenemy of the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Shredder",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Krang",
              "Bebop",
              "Rocksteady"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The Shredder, also known as Oroku Saki, is a formidable and ruthless ninja master who serves as the main adversary of the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What is the real name of the antihero known as The Punisher?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Frank Castle",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Matt Murdock",
              "Luke Cage",
              "Danny Rand"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Frank Castle, a former Marine and Vietnam War veteran, transforms into the vigilante antihero known as The Punisher after the tragic murder of his family."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which supervillain is the archnemesis of the Flash?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Reverse-Flash",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Captain Cold",
              "Gorilla Grodd",
              "Zoom"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The Reverse-Flash, also known as Eobard Thawne, is a speedster from the future and the primary nemesis of the Flash, Barry Allen."
          }
        ]
      }
    }
  ]
}